

José FortúnSoftware Developer

iosemanuelfortunromero@gmail.com

659606332

Sevilla, España

https://jfortun.github.io/

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/jmfortun/

https://github.com/JFortun

About me

I am a senior technician in Multiplatform Application Development and I am studying Software Engineering.

Currently, I work as a software developer focused mainly on the backend, programming in Java and using the Spring framework. I have experience in projects for clients from both public and private companies, using the Scrum/Agile methodology and the latest technologies in the backend field such as Spring Webflux, Spring Cloud Stream, and Kafka, among others.

My passions are programming and technology. I love acquiring new knowledge, working in a team, and solving problems, and I consider myself a proactive, efficient, and organized person who works well under pressure.

⊗ Skills

Java

Spring / SpringBoot / Spring Cloud

Kafka

REST API

Microservices arch.

Google Cloud Platform

Databases: SQL / PostgreSQL

Git / GitHub / GitLab / BitBucket

Jira / Confluence

OpenAPI / API First

GitHub Actions

Languages

Spanish *Native*

English Intermediate ••••

Professional experience

Sngular

Senior Software Developer ∂ October 2022 – present | Seville, Spain

Deloitte *⊘*

Software Developer

August 2022 - October 2022 | Seville, Spain

Junior Software Developer

July 2021 - July 2022 | Seville, Spain

Trainee

November 2020 - June 2021 | Seville, Spain

Projects

Decathlon *⊘*

International project for the private company "Decathlon" in which I am working as a backend developer using functional and reactive programming.

Technologies: Java 17, Spring Boot, Spring WebFlux, Spring Cloud Stream, Kafka, Kafka Streams, gRPC, microservices, containers, Google Cloud Platform, Git.

MyTax ∂

International project for the taxation of Brussels in which I worked on the backend development of 9 taxes in the MyTax platform, whose features include online payments, declarations, and documents among others. Technologies: Java 17, Spring Boot, JSP, monolithic architecture, SQL, SAP eCommerce, Git.

El Corte Inglés 🔗

National project for the private company "El Corte Inglés" developing microservices following the API First methodology and using the OpenAPI standard.

Technologies: Java 11, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Data JPA, SQL, microservices, containers, OpenAPI, Git.

Renfe ∂

National project for the public railway company "Renfe" developing the backend and frontend of the online payment system.

Technologies: Java 8, Spring, JSP, SQL, monolithic architecture, Git.

Education

University Degree in Software Engineering

San Antonio de Murcia University ∂

Superior Associate Technician in Development of Multiplatform Applications $Grupo\ Studium\ \mathscr O$

Medium Associate Technician in Microinformatics Systems and Networks $IES\ Axati\ \mathscr{D}$

September 2021 – present Murcia, Spain

> September 2019 – June 2021 Seville, Spain

> September 2017 – June 2019 Seville, Spain